Guide to the George Yuzawa Papers TAM.442
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Post World War II, 1938-2009
  - Subseries C: Asian American Media Monitoring, 1952-2006
    - Correspondence: Jean Carey Bond to Clive Barnes, Mar 4, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence: John Koster to George Yuzawa, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence: Shosuke Sasaki (re: appointment to Federal Communications Commission), 1973 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence: Warren Graves to Alexander H. Joseph, Oct 1973 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Dictionar Definitions of "Jap", 1957-1961 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - How to Attack the Newspaper Use of "Jap"(published by JACL), undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Newspaper Listings and Addresses, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Subseries D: Japanese American Association of New York (JAA), 1951-2001
    Subseries D: Japanese American Association (JAA) consists of administrative documents such as meeting minutes, financial reports, constitution, by-laws and correspondence that Yuzawa kept as vice president, board member and committee chair. Newsletters, flyers and programs document events that JAA helped sponsor such as the Nipponanza cultural and arts festival, Miss New York Nikkei contest and member dinner dances.
    - General, 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Anniversary Dinner (40th): Program, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Annual Meeting (27th): Agenda, Financial Reports, List of Nominees, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Board of Directors: General, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Board of Directors: Chapter By-Laws (drafts of), undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Board of Directors: Fundraising and Cost Analysis for Moving Offices, Jul 1992-Nov 1992 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Board of Directors: Meeting Minutues, Agendas, Balance Sheets and Memos, Mar 1986-Dec 1986 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Board of Directors: Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Reports and Memos, Feb 1987-Nov 1987 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Board of Directors: Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Balance Sheets and Annual Reports, Jan 1988-May 1989 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Board of Directors: Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Balance Sheets and New Member Lists, May 1992-Nov 1992 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Constitution and By-Laws, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Correspondence (general), 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Events: Calendars, Flyers and Invitations, 1987-2004 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Issei Pioneers (list of names and date of immigration), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - JAA Constitution Study Committee: Report, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - JAA News (newsletters), 1984-2001 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Japanese American Committee of New York: Japan Night Relief Show Flyer, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Miss New York Nikkei Contest: Application Forms and Program, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Miss New York Nikkei Contest: Program, Apr 26, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - New York Japan Festival, City Hall: Invitation and Program, Mar 27, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - New York Japan Festival, Proposal for, May 1993 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Nipponanza (planning meeting minutes, correspondence, critique of event), Apr 1979-May 1979 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Nipponanza: Correspondence, Apr 1979-Jun 1979 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Nipponanza: Performer Biographies, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Nipponanza: Planning Documents, Mar 1979-Apr 1979 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Nipponanza: Programs and Press, Apr 1979-May 1979 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - The Silver Bridge: Commemorating the New York-Tokyo 25th Sister City Anniversary: Magazine, Program and Flyer, May 1985-Sep 1985 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Tokyo Week Japan Day Parade: Press Release, Jun 1985 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - JAA Welfare Committee Annual Goodwill Hospital Visit: Correspondence and List of Visitees, Nov 1974 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Subseries E: Japanese American Help for the Aging (JAHFA), 1972-2007
    Subseries E: Japanese American Help for the Aging, Inc. (JAHFA) documents Yuzawa's work with the New York Japanese American elderly as JAHFA's founding director and consists of meeting minutes, financial reports, correspondence, newsletters, events flyers and resource information on elderly housing and care. The early history of JAHFA is documented through files on its various predecessor ad hoc committees, needs assessment questionnaires and grant proposals.
    - General, 1974-1996 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Ad Hoc Committee for the Elderly: Senior Citizens Questionnaire Results, Apr 16, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Ad Hoc Committee for Health Issues: Free Community Health Forum, Feb-Apr 1993 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Ad Hoc Committee for Health Issues Meeting: Minutes, Feb 1, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Ad Hoc Committee of Concerned Asians for New York: Meeting Minutes, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Ad Hoc Committee of Concerned Asians for New York: Senior Citizens Questionnaire, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Ad Hoc Committee of Concerned Asians for New York: Senior Citizens Questionnaire (in Japanese), Jun 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Housing for the Elderly: Clipping re: Questionnaire, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Articles of Incorporation, Aug 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors: Memo and Service Statistics, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Board Meetings: Minutes, Agendas, Reports and Correspondence, Jun 1976-Jun 1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Board Meetings: Minutes, Agendas and Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Constitution and By-Laws, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence re: Award to George Yuzawa from Emperor of Japan, Jan 1982-May 1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence re: Donations, Jan 1987-May 1994 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence re: Keirokai Events, 1986-1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence re: Senior Citizens Survey, Dec 1986 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Early Alert Program (for senior citizens): Information and Notes, Apr 1977 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Events: Flyers and Programs, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Financial Statements, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Financial Statements, 1987-1992 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Grant Proposals, 1974-1981 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Grant Proposal to Commission on Race and Religion, Nov 21, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Grant Proposal to New York Community Trust, Nov 21, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Grant Proposal to New York Foundation, Mar 1980 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Grant Proposal and Information, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Health Facilities Resource List, Newsletter for Seniors and Questionnaire (draft), Mar 1977-Aug 1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Health Information Pamphlets (in Japanese), 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Isabella Geriatric Center: Correspondence, Newsletter, Annual Report and Clippings, 1995-2005 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Isabella Geriatric Center Autumn Gala: Program, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - JAHFA Committee on Community Services: Meeting Minutes, Jun 1, 1977-Jul 6, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - JAHFA Newsletters (in English and Japanese), 1980-1985 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - "Japanese Americans: Cultural Diversity in Health and Illness" (study by Joan Naples, Cindy Karczewski and Mary Stoffo), undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Japanese American Social Services, Inc (JASSI): Correspondence and Clippings, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - JASSI Report (newsletters), 2004 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Mission Statement, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - West Side Federation for Senior Housing: Meeting Minutes and Correspondence, Jul 1981-Mar 2007 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - West Side Ferderation for Senior Housing: Newsletters, 1981-1989 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - West Side Federation for Senior Housing: Public Advertisement for Section 8 Housing, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Subseries F: Japanese American United Church (JAUC), 1938-2004
    Subseries F: Japanese American United Church (JAUC) consists of minutes and reports from JAUC's annual congregational meetings, Board of Directors meetings, pastoral search committee and Concerned Group of JAUC; correspondence; fellowship newsletters; event flyers and programs; and directories of members and church officers. The series also contains materials relating to the 19th Century Japanese burial plot at Willow Grove Cemetery in New Brunswick, NJ and memorial services at Cypress Hills and Mount Olivet Cemeteries. Yuzawa, as part of his advocacy work for the Japanese American elderly, regularly assisted in making funeral arrangements.
    - General, 1974-1994 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Anniversary Celebration (100th): Program, Invitations and Press Release, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Annual Congregational Meeting: Reports and Minutes, Jan 25, 1970-Jan 30, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Annual Congregational Meeting: Reports and Minutes, Jan 31, 1982-Jan 30, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Annual Congregational Meeting: Reports and Minutes, Jan 29, 1984-Jan 27, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Annual Congregational Meeting: Reports and Minutes, Jan 26, 1986-Jan 29, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Annual Congregational Meeting: Reports and Minutes, Jan 27, 1991-Jan 31, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Annual Congregational Meeting: Reports and Minutes, Jan 26, 1997-Jan 25, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Annual Congregational Meeting: Reports and Minutes, Jan 31, 1999-Feb 10, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Annual Congregational Meeting: Reports and Minutes, Jan 25, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Bazaar (fundraiser): Correspondence, Flyers, Reports, and Donor Lists, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Board of Directors: Meeting Minutes, 1987-1996 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Concerned Group of Japanese American United Church: Transcript of Meeting, Dec 10, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Constitution, By-Laws, Chronology and Committee Chairpersons List, 1978-2002 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence (general), 1995-2004 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Cries of the Hudson (booklet of sermons and testimonies), 2001 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Cypress Hills Cemetery, Brooklyn, NY: Maps, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Cypress Hills Cemetery, Brooklyn, NY: Tom Hayashi Memorial Vault, 1980-1999 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Cypress Hills Cemetery and Woodlawn Cemetery: Maps and Funeral Arrangements, 1983-2003 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Directories of Church Members, 1988-1995 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Events: Flyers and Programs, 1975-1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Pastoral Search Committee: Memorandum and Meeting Notes, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - JAUC Women's Fellowship Newsletters, Oct 1972-Apr 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - List of Church Officers, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Mount Olivet Japanese Cemetery: Memorial Day Service, 1984-2001 (Box 5, Folder 6, Folder 5)
    - Weekly Bulletin (JAUC newsletters), 1972-1988 (Box 5, Folder 6, Folder 7)
    - Willow Grove Cemetery, New Brunswick, NJ: 19th Century Japanese Burial Plot: Correspondence (in English and Japanese), 1967-1980 (Box 5, Folder 8, Folder 7)
    - Willow Grove Cemetery, New Brunswick, NJ: 19th Century Japanese Burial Plot: Papers, Maps, and Clippings, 1938-1978 (Box 5, Folder 9, Folder 8)
    - Willow Grove Cemetery, New Brunswick, NJ: 19th Century Japanese Burial Plot: Report, 1967-1994 (Box 5, Folder 10, Folder 9)
  - Subseries G: Personal Documents, Correspondence, and Subject Files, 1949-2009
    Subseries G: Personal Documents, Correspondence, and Subject Files consists of personal documents, correspondence and subject files relating to Asian American organizations and individuals in which Yuzawa took an interest or active part. There are substantial files relating to the Sakura Matsuri (Cherry Blossom Festival) that Yuzawa was instrumental in establishing at the Brooklyn Botanic Garden and the Japanese American Citizens League (JACL) New York Chapter, of which Yuzawa was a board member. Most other organizations have one file with contents ranging from event programs and flyers to correspondence, newsletters and member lists. The series also contains Yuzawa's personal documents such as resumes and awards, birth and marriage certificates, medical records, memory writing exercises and personal correspondence. Yuzawa avidly collected and archived information about Asian American events and people. The files he kept on individuals, some of whom he knew personally, range in content from clippings to more personal documents such as correspondence, resumes and ID cards.
    - General (flyers, pamphlets, notes), 1960-1998 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Asian American Federation: "Strength in Diversity" Conference Program, May 26, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Asian Americans for Jesse Jackson: Flyer, Feb 7, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Asian Coalition: Flyer, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Asian & Pacific Islander Coalition on HIV/AIDS (APICHA), 1992-2004 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Branch Brook Park (New Jersey), Sakura Matsuri: Correspondence, Programs and Maps, 1991-2004 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Japanese/American Business Council: Membership Invitation and Request for Sponsorship, Feb 1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden: Map and Self-Guided Tour (brochures in English and Japanese), undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden: Newsletter and Press Release, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Sakura Matsuri: General, 1984-2005 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Sakura Matsuri: Flyers, Poster and Schedule of Events, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Sakura Matsuri: Japanese American Cultural Committee Stationary, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Sakura Matsuri: Mayoral and Governor's Proclamation, May 1982 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Sakura Matsuri: Planning Committee (mostly correspondence), Nov 1981-May 1982 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Sakura Matsuri: Posters and Schedules of Events, 1982-1997 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "The Chinese Garment Industry in New York City" (student paper), May 10, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Clipping from Nikkei Heritage: "Japanese American Moral Values and Behavioral Norms", Winter 2000 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Clippings re: Interviews of George Yuzawa on Pearl Harbor (movie), May 2001 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Clippings re: Little Tokyo, Los Angeles, 1995-2002 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Committee for July 4th in Old New York: Memo to Parade Float Applicants, May 24, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence: Aiko Herzig Yoshinaga, 1999-2009 (Box 5, Folder 29A)
    - Correspondence: Ed Koch to George Yuzawa and Komataro Kishi, Aug 17, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 29B)
    - Correspondence: George Yuzawa to Donald Rumsfeld, 1999-2003 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence: George Yuzawa to Indian Civil Rights Division, U.S. Department of Justice, Jun 11, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence: Mario M. Cuomo to Komataro Kishi, Masako Nishi and Yae Yanase, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 31A)
    - Correspondence: Norman Y. Mineta to George Yuzawa, 1988-2002 (Box 5, Folder 31B)
    - Correspondence: Robert and Carolyn Goodman to George Yuzawa (re: death of Andrew Goodman), Jul 15, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence: Ronald Reagan to George Yuzawa, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 32A)
    - Correspondence (general): George Yuzawa, 1964-1992 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Friends of the Obayashi Family (funds for Kazu Obayashi and Family), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Grand Sumo Tournament, Madison Square Garden: Programs, Jun 1985 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Harmonia Opera Company, Inc.: Correspondence re: Rehearsal Space in Japanese American Churches, 1984-1998 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Hashimoto, Henry: Travel Itinerary, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Hattori, Walter Seikichi: Funeral Service Program, Mar 11, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Issei Oral History Project: Issei Christians (transcripts of selected interviews), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - JACL: Correspondence re: Charles Kubokawa's Proposal for a National Senior Citizens Center, Nov 2, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - JACL: Correspondence re: Minority Health Fair Program, Jan 19, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - JACL: Correspondence: Robert T. Matsui to George Yuzawa, Aug 18, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - JACL: Events: Programs and Flyers, 1973-2004 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - JACL: "The Future of JACL" (typescript contemplating dissolving NY chapter), [1973] (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - JACL National Convention: Meeting Minutes, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - JACL New York Chapter Newsletters, 1978-1985 (Box 5, Folder 46A, Folder 46)
    - Japanese American Lions Club: List of Members and Addresses, Nov 1987 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Japanese American Veterans Association (JAVA): Luncheon Honoring Jack and Aiko Herzig: Minutes/Report, Nov 8, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Japan Society: Dinner Given in Honor of Crown Prince of Japan: Program and Menu, Sep 17, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Kinney, Pat: Correspondence and Clippings, Jun 1999-Jan 2004 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Kishikawa, Hyotaro: Personal Documents, Jun 17, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Kobo Abe Studio Production of "The Little Elephant is Dead: An Exhibition of Images": Programs, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Konokawa, Asae: As I Remember (memoir), May-Jun 1992 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Konokawa, [Asae]: Testimonial Given in Church (about her husband and Rev. Matsunaga), Jun 23, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Mirikatani, Jimmy: Invitation, Correspondence and Clippings, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Museum of Chinese in the Americas: "Allies and Enemies: The Dilemma of Asian Americans During World War II" (public programming brochure), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Music from Japan: Concert at Carnegie Hall: Flyer, Correspondence and List of Attendees, Jan-Feb 1984 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - National Asian American Mental Health Conference: Poster of Delegates and Schedule, Apr 27-29, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - National Federation of Asian American United Methodists: Newsletter and Membership Brochure, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - National Japanese American Historical Society: Americans of Japanese Ancestry and the United States Constitution (commemorative booklet), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - National Japanese American Historical Society: Centennial of U.S. Constitution Opening Ceremonies: Programs and Schedules, Oct 1987 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - National Japanese American Historical Society: Nikkei Heritage Newsletters, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 61A, Folder 51A)
    - New York Coalition for Asian/Pacific American Heritage Festival: Flyers and Press Release, May 1979 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - New York Peace Pagada Committee: Proposal for Peace Pagoda on Roosevelt Island, New York, undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Nisei Investors of New York: Agenda, Club Rules and Procedures and Partner Agreement, 1972-1979 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Nisei Investors of New York: Member List and Contact Information, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Nisei Week Japanese Festival in Los Angeles, CA (37th Annual): Program Booklet, Aug 1977 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Pacific Citizen (newspaper), 1971-1999 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Ports, Suki: Resume and 70th Birthday, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Reformed Church in America: General Synod Festival, Albany, NY: Program and Paper re: Incarceration (presented by George Yuzawa), Jun 1992 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Roosevelt High School, Los Angeles, CA: Real Estate Option, Mar 1964 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Sasaki, Shosuke: Resume, Oct 1967 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Soh Daiko: Flyer, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Sugihara, Chiune: Clippings and Correspondence re: Holocaust Oral History Project, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - United Asian Communities Center Bulletin (newsletter), Jun 1974 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - United States Commission on Civil Rights, New York State Advisory Committee: The Forgotten Minority: Asian Americans in New York City (report), Nov 1977 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - U.S. National Arboretum: The Japanese Flowering Cherry Trees of Washington, D.C. (publication), Dec 1977 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Watanabe, Ruth: Correspondence, Clippings and Obituary, 1970-2005 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - York College, CUNY: "Asian Culture: Tradition and Diaspora" Conference Program, Oct 27, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Yoshida, Takashi: "Standing Loyally by the Flag: The Experience of People of Japanese Ancestry in New York During World War II" (draft of paper), undated (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Yuzawa Family Photographs (printed on paper), Mar 21, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Yuzawa, George: Award from Emperor of Japan (Fifth Class of the Order of the Sacred Treasure), Nov 1983-Feb 1984 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Yuzawa, George: Birth and Marriage Certificates (photocopies), Feb 21, 1915-Aug 4, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Yuzawa, George: Book Purchases and Copies of Excerpts, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Yuzawa, George: Event Invitations and Thank Yous, 1974-1997 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Yuzawa, George: Flight Itinerary for trip to Amache, Colorado, Nov 1991 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Yuzawa, George: Memory Writing Exercises, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Yuzawa, George: Park Central Florist Delivery Tag, undated (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Yuzawa, George: Physical Examination Report, 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Yuzawa, George: Resume and Chronology; Obituaries, undated, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Yuzawa, George: Volunteer Work and Awards (chronology, programs, correspondence, clippings), 1982-2003 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Yuzawa-Ruben, Patricia: Notes Accompanying Addition to George Yuzawa Papers, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 91)
- Series III: Oversize, Ephemera and Printed Materials, 1942-1999
  Series consists of ephemera such as posters and buttons and printed materials such as books and copies of the Japanese American community newspaper New York Nichibei. Of note are several items separated from Series I: Early Life and WWII because of size or format. These include James T. Yuzawa's personal notebook and scrapbook of clippings and "souvenir albums" (scrapbooks) of the Amache Consumer Enterprises co-op and the Military Intelligence Service Language School (MISLS).
  - Amache Co-op Souvenir Album, Amache Colorado, [1940s] (Box 6)
  - Elementary Japanese for University Students Texts (textbook), 1942 (Box 6)
  - Frank Fujii's "Call to Arms" Redress Movement Logo: Buttons (multiple duplicates), undated (Box 7)
  - Frank Fujii's "Call to Arms" Redress Movement Logo: Oversize Poster (signed by Fujii), undated (Box 7)
  - GHQ Enlisted Club, Tokyo: General Headquarters, Far East Command (scrapbook), 1946 (Box 6)
  - Graph of America: The Imperial Visit of the Emperor and Empress of Japan to the United States (book), 1976 (Box 6)
  - The Honorable Elders: A Cross-Cultural Analysis of Aging in Japan (book), 1975 (Box 6)
  - Japanese Indigenous Orchids in Colour (book), 1981 (Box 6)
  - Military Intelligence Service Language School (MISLS) Album, 1946 (Box 6)
  - National Japanese American Memorial Foundation Ground Breaking in Washington, DC: Button; Park Central Florist, Gift Tags; V-E Day St. Patrick's Cathedral, NY, NY, Prayer Card., 1999; undated; 1945 (Box 7)
  - New York Nichibei (newspaper), 1971 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - New York Nichibei (newspaper), 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - New York Nichibei (newspaper), 1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - New York Nichibei (newspaper), 1978-1983 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - New York Nichibei (newspaper), 1988-1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Pacific Stars and Stripes...the First Year: Dependent Housing (oversize news magazine), Sep 2, 1946 (Box 7)
  - Pan American Yearbook, 1945 (Box 6)
  - Picture Travel Book on Hida Takayama, Japan, undated (Box 6)
  - Tokyo Walking Map: Guidebook for Visiting Businesspeople and Tourists, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Yuzawa, James T.: Date Book (personal notebook), 1946 (Box 6)